In the first code cell we load the MNIST data set
最初のコードセルで MNIST データセットをロードします
which comes pre-installed with TensorFlow.
これは TensorFlow と共にプリインストールされます
Then we store the training validation and test sets.
その後 トレーニング 検証 テストセットを保存します
Next, we verify that the number of images in each set
次に 各セットの画像の数が
matches the number of labels in the same set.
同じセットのラベルの数と一致することを確認します
Then, we print out the shape of one image
次に 1 つの画像の形状を出力して
so that we know what the dimensions of the data are.
そのデータの次元を把握します
Finally, we print out the size of each set.
最後に 各セットのサイズを出力します
When we run the code,
このコードを実行すると
we see that the training set has 55,000 images.
トレーニングセットの画像数 55,000 が表示されます
The validation set has 5,000 images and the test set has 10,000 images.
評価セットの画像数は 5,000 で テストセットの画像数は 10,000 です
In the next code cell we transformed the 28 by 28
次のコードセルでは 28x28 の
MNIST images into 32 by 32 images that LeNet can process.
MNIST 画像を LeNet で処理可能な 32x32 の画像に変換しました
We could do this by using image processing software to scale up each image.
これを行うために画像処理ソフトウェアを使用して各画像を拡大しました
But here, we just pad the images with zeroes around the edges.
ただし 画像のエッジ周囲にゼロを埋め込んでいます
This is much faster and it works well.
このほうが高速でうまく動作します
When we've done, the image shape is 32 by 32 by 1
完成すると 画像の形状は 32x32x1 になります
which is exactly what LeNet takes as input.
これは LeNet への入力そのものです
It's always a good idea to visualize our data
使用するデータを視覚化することは常に得策です
to make sure that everything actually looks the way we think it does.
すべてが実際に 想定したようになっていることを確認できます
In this case, we select a random image
この場合 ランダムな画像を 1 つ
from the training set and we use matplotlib to visualize it.
トレーニングセットから選び matplotlib によって視覚化します
Then we also print out the label for that image.
次に その画像のラベルも出力します
Happily, this label matches the image, one-one.
幸いにもこのラベルは画像と一致します  1 と 1 です
In the next cell we preprocess the data
次のセルでデータを前処理します
which in this case just amounts to shuffling the training set.
この場合 トレーニングセットをシャッフルするという意味です
It's important to shuffle the training data otherwise
トレーニングデータのシャフルは重要です  そうしないと
the ordering of the data might have a huge effect on how well the network trends.
データの順序がネットワークの学習結果に大きく影響することがあります